哎呀 总算出场了
Ay, finally!
看看谁穿着迷你比基尼闪亮登场了
Look who's wearing her itsy-bitsy bikini.
同志之言 不算调戏
He can comment because he's gay.
他是在说莉莉
He was talking about Lily.
我也是
So was I.
小卡 你把她打扮得太漂亮了
Ay, Cam, you make her look so pretty.
猜猜谁圣诞节不过来了
Guess who's not coming for Christmas.
你比女儿抢镜多了
And the spotlight shifts.
-老妈 她不来了 -什么
- Mom. She cancelled. - What?
没有道歉 只有留言
In a voice mail, no less.
难以置信 好吧 其实完全可以置信
Unbelievable--and by that, I mean believable.
外婆为啥不来了啊
Why isn't Nana coming?
不知道 好像她新男友
I don't know. Something about her new boyfriend
硬要拽她去游轮巡航
whisking her away on a cruise.
-她不来算是对我的大礼了 -什么男友
- I just got my gift. - What boyfriend?
游轮船长卡尔
Carl the cruise ship captain.
她的节日简讯里写着呢
It was in her holiday newsletter.
那玩意我可读不下去
Oh, I can't read that whole thing. No.
是啊 前两页都在讲她勇救小鸟
Yeah, after two pages about the bird she rescued...
顺便一提
And by the way,
鸟都死了 怎么能算是救了它
I don't think you can say you rescued something if it dies.
-鸟死了吗 -她还为此写了首诗呢
- It died? - She wrote a poem about it.
在我看来 就算作为自由体诗歌也太过飘忽
A little too free with the free verse for my taste,
不过算了 姑且当它是首诗吧
but fine, we'll call it a poem.
我看到她写要起诉她的读书俱乐部时 就看不下去了
I stopped reading after she talked about suing her book club.
我只看到"亲爱的朋友们
Oh, I stopped reading after "Dear friends,
家人们以及闲杂人等..."
Family and others..."
对不起 谁是"闲杂人等"
I'm sorry. Who are "Others"?
-我呗 -你才不是...
- Me. - No, you're not...
好吧 也许是指你
Uh, maybe you are.
其实吧 她圣诞节表现算好的了
Actually, she's kind of at her best at Christmas.
她烤的"薄饼干"很不错
She makes a mean cookie.
她除了刻"薄"还会什么
What other kind could she possibly make?
真可怜
Aw, it's so sad that
今年你们不能和妈妈共度圣诞了
you guys are not gonna be with your mom this Christmas.
-其实还好 -岂止还好
- It's fine. - Yeah, it's more than fine.
我们还是 我们别再谈妈了吧
Let's just-- can we move off of mom?
赶紧的
Yes, please.
米奇尔 往好的方面想
Yeah, and the upside now, Mitchell--
我们圣诞节可以去密苏里了
We can spend Christmas in Missouri
那里才真的有圣诞气氛呢
where it actually feels like Christmas.
等等 慢点 妈妈不来
Wait. Hang on a second. Just because Mom isn't coming
不代表我们不能在一起过圣诞啊
doesn't mean we're not gonna spend Christmas together.
与家人团聚才是重点啊
I mean, it's about family.
你觉得我们是去密苏里看谁的 克莱尔
Who do you think we're seeing in Missouri, claire,
-橡树岭男孩? -等等
- The Oak Ridge Boys? - Hold on.
今年的平安夜不是说好一起过吗
I thought we were all getting together Christmas Eve this year.
25号我们就飞去墨西哥了
We're on a flight to Mexico the 25th.
说什么呢 你们25号就要飞走
What do you mean, you're getting on a flight on the 25th?
是你们俩要和妈妈相处
You two needed time with your mom.
我早就忍了你们的妈妈很多年了
I've already served my time with your mom.
-老爸啊 -好吧
- Oh, Dad. - Well, uh,
那我们什么时候过圣诞节呢
well, when are we gonna have Christmas then?
我听说墨西哥有很多人贩子专门拐小孩
I heard kids are getting snatched in Mexico.
什么
What?
美国人贩子也不少
Kids get snatched here just as much.
司空见惯了 别害怕
It happens all the time. Don't be scared.
"司空见惯"难道是指...
Now when you say "All the time"
好了 下周末怎么样
Okay, well what about next weekend?
因为我们21号前在家 对吧
Cause we're only home till the 21st, right?
我们明天离家 21号才回来
Yeah, we leave tomorrow and we don't come back until the 21st.
数学精 能帮我拿杯柠檬水吗
Hey, math club, could you get me some more lemonade?
难道说今天是圣诞节前
Are we saying that this is the last time
我们全家人最后一次相聚吗
we're all gonna be together as a family until after the holidays?
对你来说 可能是人生最后一次了
And for you, maybe ever.
这太糟了
Well, this stinks.
对啊 这可不行 不能这样
Yeah, we can't do this. This is not right.
圣诞节一直都是一起过的
We always spend Christmas together.
对 我们得想想法子才行
Yeah, we have to do something about it.
等 等等 大家收声
Ho, ho, hold up a sec.
我们今天都没事
We're all free today.
有4个小时可以购物 煮菜 包礼物 买圣诞树
We've got four hours to shop, cook, wrap, get a tree.
到了晚上
By tonight,
我们就可以共度圣诞不是吗
we could be celebrating Christmas, right?
我觉得应该可行
I-I guess we could do that.
当然可行啦
Of course we can!
你们听说过"特快圣诞"吗
Have you ever heard of express Christmas?
-没有 -肯定没有 这是我刚发明的
- No. - No, you haven't, because I just invented it.
特快圣诞 菲尔专利
Express Christmas, "Tm."
-就是无法圣诞当天庆祝节日... -我明白
- It's when you can't have it on Christmas day... - I got it.
-只好提前速成 -行动吧
- And you have to scramble. - Get on with it!
-行了行了 -大家速度 时间不等人
- Yeah, yeah... - We're wasting time! We're wasting time!
全体进屋 好好计划一下
Everyone in the house! We'll make a plan!
时间不等... 烫 地面晒得好烫
Time is of the--oh! Ow! Hot! Hot! It's just too hot!
-菲尔小心 -啊呀
- Oh, Phil! - Aah!
-我们真要这么做吗 -对
- So we're really doing this, huh? - Yes.
-当然了 -平安夜事项我都安排好了
- Yeah. - 'cause I had stuff lined up for Christmas Eve.
当然了 杰
Yeah, Jay.
也是曼尼享受家庭圣诞的最后机会哦
It's Manny's last chance to enjoy a family Christmas.
你是想说 今年的最后机会吧
Until next year, you mean.
那么多人贩子...
Well, with all the snatchings...
别吓我了 卢克
Get out of my head, Luke!
好 谁去买圣诞树
Okay, who's gonna get the tree?
我去我去
Oh! I will. I will.
一旦买错 有人会不高兴的
Because, you know, get the wrong kind, people get upset.
-只有你会不高兴 -我也是人
- You get upset. - I'm people.
好 我去买火鸡 礼物呢
Fine, I'll get the turkey. What about gifts?
杰 礼物都买了吗
Jay, did we finish shopping?
买完了 不过还没包好
Yeah, but we're not wrapped.
那个我可以帮忙
Oh, I can help with that.
我们有个可移动礼品包装站
We have a mobile wrapping station.
那家伙 可真是物超所值
God, has that thing paid for itself.
是吗 我怎么觉得是我买的单
Really? Cause I feel like I paid for it.
行 灯和装饰品在我们家
Okay. We've got lights and ornaments at our place.
万事俱备 只差什么呢
Oh! You know what would be great?
-只差小天使 -小天使
- Is the angel! - The angel.
-对 在哪呢 -歌洛莉亚
- Yeah. Where is it? - Oh. Um, Gloria,
在你阁楼里呢 你能去找下吗
It's up in your attic. Would you get it?
不是吧 最讨厌阁楼了
Ay, no! Not the attic!
又脏又乱 还有蜘蛛
It's dirty, and there are spiders.
但如果不拿的话 就没有圣诞气氛了
Oh, but it really won't be Christmas without it.
就算拿了也没有圣诞气氛 今天才12月16号
Won't be Christmas with it. It's December 16th.
卢克可以帮歌洛莉亚找 他不害怕
Luke will help Gloria. He's not scared.
太好了 阁楼那种地方我从不去
Oh, good. You won't find me in any attic.
或许你的尸体最终就在阁楼里被发现的
That may be exactly where they find you.
妈
Mom!
我今晚有个派对
Uh, I have a party tonight.
你说过如果考试拿到B 我就可以去的
You promised I could go if I got a "B" On my test.
我忍痛复习了 我屈尊翻书了
I studied. I read stuff.
不让去的话 我学习有什么意义啊
What was the point of all that?
-学习的意义在于 姑娘 -你们忘了吗
- The point, young lady ... - Who can remember,
特快圣诞9点就要完工的
Express Christmas will be done by 9:00.
克莱尔 我待会把礼物清单短信给你
Claire, I'll text you the gift list.
行
Okay.
你跟海莉去购物
You and Haley do the shopping.
曼尼 你跟我一起 我们去置办年货
Manny, you're coming with me. We're gonna get groceries.
6点晚餐 齐聚我家 不见不散
Dinner, our house, 6:00.
行动吧
Let's move!
飞驰吧 阿冲 小舞 跳豆 悍妇
On Dasher! On Dancer! On Prancer and Vixen!
嘿 我真是妙语连珠啊
Hey, that kind of worked out.
别磨蹭了 海莉
Come on, Haley.
杰 你肯定会爱死这包装纸
Jay, you are gonna love this wrapping paper--
很有趣的
It'll be fun.
很好玩的 我们去塔吉特好吗
A lot of fun. We can go to Target. Okay?
-伙计们 我在想 -出门了出门了
- I was just wo-- you guys. - Let's go! Let's go!
快点 走啦
Come on, let's go!
这么说 就我跟莉莉去买树吗
So it's--it's just me and Lily getting the tree, then?
-有人吗 -有人吗
- Hello? - Hello?
我妈发短信告诉我今天"圣快"?
My mom tells me it's "Xmas" in a text?
总比我妈好 甩条留言就放我们鸽子
Yeah, well, my mom canceled in a voice mail
用条简讯通知我们她谈了新男友
and told me she had a boyfriend in a newsletter,
所以 欢迎加入悲情二人组
So... Join the team.
穿上外套吧 咱要去买圣诞树
Put some clothes on. We're getting a tree.
卢克
Luke!
看哪儿
At what?
什么叫"看哪儿" 我说的是"卢克"
What do you mean, "at what"? I said "Luke."
我在看啊
I am looking.
我知道你在看 乖乖待在横梁上
I know you are. Stay on the beams.
可能在这儿
Maybe it's here.
天呐 见鬼了 又来了
Ay, dios mio! El diablo! It's back!
话说 那小天使有什么特别的
What is so special about that angel, anyways?
我不知道
I don't know.
估计是外婆给妈妈和米奇尔舅舅做的
I guess nana made it for mom and uncle Mitchell
小时候的玩具
when they were kids.
哇 真幸福
Ay, that's nice.
"看着"脚下[歧义:卢克 你去哪]
Look where you're going!
去开其他箱子
To open more boxes.
你刚刚说的是"小心脚下的地板" 是吗
Oh, you said "look where you're going," didn't you?
是的
Yes.
每次你说"卢克"的时候
Every time you said "Luke",
我都以为你说的是"看"
I though you said "look".
我觉得发音一样啊
I don't hear the difference.
不难区分的 "一个"是我的名字
It's not that hard. One is my name.
你才不叫"一哥"呢
Juan is not your name!
别老开玩笑 看着点 卢克
Stop kidding around and look, Luke!
我懂了 "看"听起来和"卢克"很像
Ay, I get it. "look" sounds like "Luke."
你终于懂了 感谢上帝
Yes. Thank god.
我都被你叫错三年了
I've been carrying that one around for three years.
天呐 购物清单列了近百条
Ugh. There's like a hundred things on this list.
我知道 母女同心 其利断金 多有趣啊
I know, but it's just the two of us. It's fun.
拜托 是假圣诞节 又不是假装母亲节
Okay, it's not Fake Mother's Day.
这个地方实在太大了
Ugh! This place is huge!
而且我们还要做晚餐
Oh, plus we have to cook dinner!
简直是不可能完成的任务
This is impossible.
听着
Listen to me.
你前半生的努力 就为此一战
Your whole life has led to this moment.
所有的训练 付出的时间
All the training, the hours of dedication...
世上简直没有任何人
There's not a soul alive who can touch you
在购物上能比得过你
when it comes to shopping,
宝贝儿 你是知道的
and, baby, you know it.
看着我
Look at me.
拿出你的本事来
Be you.
把清单给我
Give me that list.
真心自豪啊
Never been more proud in my life.
-来吧 -等等
- Come on. - No.
走这边
This way.
这棵怎么样
What about this one?
让我看看 不 不行
Let's see. No. No.
对不起 我知道我现在有点强迫症
I'm sorry, I know I'm being really O.C.D. right now,
但我想找到完全合意的那一棵
But there's something very particular that I'm looking for.
必须是花旗松 至少8英尺高
It needs to be a douglas fir, at least 8 feet tall,
而且360度无死角
and look good from all sides.
完全同意 不能有秃枝
Exactly. No bald spots.
对 谢谢理解
Yes. Thank you. Thank you.
关键是要对称的树 是吧
The key is symmetry, right?
*哦 对称树 哦 对称树*
* O, symmetry. O, symmetry *
为什么我们从来没有一起逛过街
How come we never go shopping together?
-因为我讨厌逛街 -我也是
- Because I hate shopping. - I do, too!
-来看看这棵 -看看
- Okay, this one. - Wait.
-不行不行 -不行 完全不行
- Oh. No, no, no. - Oh, no, no, no, no.
我大概知道你们想要哪种了
Uh, I think I know what you're looking for,
我们刚到一批货 一定合你们心意
And we just got a shipment that might be perfect for you.
没搞错吧
Okay, wow.
虽然我舅舅基态毕露
Just because my uncle is clearly gay...
-先别 -但未必就喜欢你们的恶俗粉红树
- Let's not... - doesn't mean he'd ever want your tacky pink tree.
坦白讲 我们宁愿把衣帽架改成圣诞树
And frankly, we'd rather throw some lights on a coatrack
也不愿意跟你这种肥仔做买卖
than have to deal with knuckle-draggers like you
白白糟蹋了这大好节日
today of all days.
12月16日
December 16th.
好吧 首先呢 了不起的演讲
Okay, first of all, amazing.
-再者 -我指的是那辆卡车
- Second of all... - I was pointing to the truck.
里面都是8英尺高的花旗松
It's full of 8-foot douglas-firs.
在那棵粉色小树后面
It's behind the pink tree.
再者
Second of all,
我们 我们打算买这棵 这棵树
Uh, we're--we're gonna go ahead and take, uh, this--this tree...
就那棵
That one.
而且我们打算自己把它运到车上
And we're going to tie it onto our car ourselves.
我也没打算帮你
You bet you will.
-我有两个爹地 -人家懂的 莉莉
- I have two daddies. - He gets it, Lily.
小卡和杰 听起来像小鸟的名字
Cam and Jay--you know, sort of sounds like a bird.
"小卡和杰的迁徙路线"
"The migratory patterns of the Cam and Jay..."
你那抽屉里还有胶带吗
Do you have any more tape in that thing?
我那抽屉里还有没有胶带呢
Do I have more tape in that?
有满满一箱呢 先生
I got a tank full of tape, Mister.
你想要哪种 透明胶 抛光胶
What do you want? Invisible? Satin finish?
-还是双面胶 -随便 都行
- Uh, double-sided? - Whatever. Whatever.
有点儿意思
That's interesting.
我可不觉得 不过你指的什么
I doubt that it is, but what?
我是说你包礼物的方式
Well, I mean the way you wrap a gift.
你用了很多胶带 像是对别人设防
That's a lot of tape. Nobody can get in.
就好像 你知道的
Kind of like... You know...
我想说 你接受了我
I mean, well, you let me in,
但是总体来说
But in general, w--
为什么要用那么多胶带呢 杰
Why so much tape, Jay?
你穿毛衣干什么
Why are you wearing a sweater
外面现在95华氏度[约35摄氏度]
when it's 95 degrees out?
这是我的圣诞毛衫啊
It's my Christmas sweater.
上面汗迹斑斑
Based on those stains,
你是圣诞"汗衫"才对吧
you are the Christmas sweater.
看看 谁是最孝顺的人
Well, who's been a very good boy?
来
So...
好吧 我们直接"打开天窗说亮话"
Okay. Are we gonna talk about the elephant in the room,
不过真讽刺 礼物跟大象比实在太小了
which is ironic because it's so tiny?
男人之间不会送这么小只的礼物
A man doesn't give another man a gift this small.
你以为那是什么 求婚戒指吗
Oh, what do you think it is, a ring?
这瓶塞是有塞着酒的吧
Was there wine with this cork?
没错 喝这酒的时候我们在
Yes, there was, and we drank it on...
喝这酒的时候我们在...什么
Oh, we drank it on, uh... Eh?
在那艘船上
On that boat.
你完全不记得了
You have no idea.
小卡 我连自己的周年纪念日都记不住
I can't even remember my own anniversary, Cam.
怎么还会记得和儿婿喝酒的事儿
How would I have remembered having had wine with my son's boyfriend?
不 我总是这样 这是我的错
No, I do this. This is my fault.
我赋予了这东西太多的感情意义
I-I attach too much meaning to things.
5年前 那是我们第一次同看橄榄球比赛
I mean, we watched our first football game together five years ago,
那时你用一瓶酒招待我
and I feel the need to save the cork
我觉得意义重大 故把瓶塞留作纪念
from the bottle of wine you served.
谁会做这样的傻事呢
I mean, who does that?
对了 这不是我送你的唯一礼物
It's not your only gift, by the way.
那儿的盒子里有一个复制的酒瓶
There's a duplicate bottle in that box right over there
上面有我亲手刻的日期
which I had engraved with the date
还有比赛得分 我就是有问题
and the final score, because I have a problem.
太多愁善感
I feel too much.
我得去克莱尔那儿逛逛
I gotta get going to Claire's.
-小卡 -不 新伤脆弱 请别撒盐
- Cam...- No. Fresh wound. Can't talk yet.
行 就用瓶塞塞住伤口吧
Fine. We'll put a cork in it.
让伤口愈合吧 杰
Let it scab, Jay.
让伤口慢慢愈合
Let it scab.
你在这呢 我还以为你走丢了
Oh, there you are. I thought I'd lost you.
不好意思 我刚刚试了下蒲团
Oh, I'm sorry. I may have taken a few minutes to try out a futon.
那是给年轻姑娘用的
It's a young woman's game.
好了 进展如何
Okay. Where do we stand?
-万事俱备 -太棒了
- I think we have everything. - Yes!
只欠莉莉的瓢虫小夜灯
Oh... Except the ladybug night-light for Lily.
海莉 你此生就为了此刻...
Haley, your whole life has led up...
明白 妈 明白得很
Oh, I got it, Mom, I got it.
那就好 我先去排队
Okay, okay, I'll b-- I'll see you in the line.
喂 罗纳德
Yes, Ronald?
终于找到了 还是最后一个
I not only found it, I got the last one.
没错 瓢虫的 不是海龟的
Yes, the ladybug, not the turtle.
玩偶也买到了 一切俱全
I also got the doll, so I'm all set.
我再逛五分钟就走
I'm gonna leave in five.
要不就用纸袋吧
Or maybe I just want paper.
纸袋 纸袋 都用纸袋
Paper. Paper. Just paper all the way. Yeah.
海莉快点啊
Haley!
我能再改变主意吗
Too late to change my mind?
先生 需要我帮您拿着手中商品
Sir, would you like me to hold your merchandise
等您逛完了 我在收银台等您
up at the register while you finish shopping?
你真贴心
Oh. Aren't you a dream?
谢谢
Thank you.
来包口香糖
Pack of gum.
再...来包口香糖
And... One more pack of gum.
逢年过节人们总爱登门拜访 你懂的
People drop in this time of year, you know.
不好意思 抱歉 借过
Excuse me. Sorry. Pardon me.
抱歉 不好意思
Sorry. Excuse me.
女士 这是您要的小夜灯
Night-light you were looking for, ma'am.
帮她刷一下 麦迪森
Ring her up, Madison.
多谢
Thank you.
给
There you go.
你要把我一个人扔这吗
You're leaving me alone here?
不不不不 我...
No, no, no, no. I...
两分钟后就回
It'll, uh, it'll just take me two minutes.
我得给杰买一个绝密又特别的礼物
I need to get Jay's supersecret special gift.
骗谁呢 先是在杂货店让我走丢
Great. First you lose me in the grocery store,
现在又把我丢在废弃的停车场
now I'm in a deserted parking lot.
干脆在我身上贴一张"求领养"的字条得了
Why don't you just put a sign on me that says "Free kid"?
我觉得那人就是了
I think that might be him.
你都不知道对方是谁啊
You don't know the guy we're meeting?
分类广告网站就是那样的
That's how Craigslist works.
你从陌生人那买到东西
Total strangers sell you things
比如说老的签名棒球卡
like signed vintage baseball cards
整个下午岳父都会对我肃然起敬
that make your father-in-law respect you for an afternoon.
我觉得来者不善
I don't like the looks of this guy.
他就是一普通人啊
He looks like everybody else.
回头你也这么跟警察说吧 犯罪画像专家
Great. You can just tell that to the police, sketch artist.
买乔·德玛吉奥的吗
Joe Dimaggio?
我是菲尔·邓菲 不过经常有人认错
Phil Dunphy, but I get that a lot.
开个玩笑 我就是买家
Kidding. I'm your guy.
能看看现金吗
Can I see the cash?
可以 那 那能看看卡吗
Yes. Can I... Can I see the card?
保存得真完好啊
Mint condition.
所以我得加价五十
That's why I want another $50.
我身上就两百
I only have the $200.
那算了
Uh, deal's off, then.
别啊 今天可是圣诞节
Come on. It's Christmas...
我家的圣诞节 说来话长
At our house. It's a long story.
我刚刚把现金都花了
I just spent all my cash on groceries.
好吧 那把"小胖墩"给我
Fine. But I'm taking the butterball.
-那样不好吧 -够了
- I don't know about that. - That's it.
我要出动妈妈小帮手了
I'm getting mother's little helper.
-什么 -我妈给了一把电击枪以防不测
- What? - My mom keeps a stun gun for emergencies.
哪有什么不测...
This isn't an emergen--
现在有了
Now it is.
我以为他要绑架我
I thought he was going to snatch me.
"小胖墩"不是说你
A butterball isn't...
他说什么
What'd he say?
我觉得好像是 "小胖墩指的是火鸡"
I think he said, "A butterball's a turkey."
我刚要去拿火鸡来着
I was reaching for the turkey.
你不能把火鸡拿走
Oh. Well, we can't give you our turkey.
让他拿吧
Yes, we can.
把钱拿走
And... Here's the... money.
球卡给我
Joe Dimaggio!
Joe Dimaggio.
谢了
Thanks.
完好无损
Mint condit--
近乎完好
Near-mint con--
可以将就
Fair condit--
废纸一张
Garbage.
我从没见过这个
Huh. Never saw this before.
"给宝贝们的天使 爱你们的妈妈"
"An angel for my angels. Love, Mom."
真温馨
Oh, that's beautiful.
而且闻起来就像外婆身上的樟脑丸味
And it smells like mothballs, just like nana.
卢克...
Luke...
-谢...圣诞快乐 -别徒劳了
- Thank--Merry Christmas. - Just--just give it up.
他恨我们
He hates us.
别妄自菲薄
Don't beat yourself up.
我几乎每周都会碰上这种事
I do that, like, once a week.
往好了想 咱以后不会来了
The good news is, we never have to come back here.
当心
Watch out!
-树遭殃了 -我不忍心看
- The tree! - I can't watch!
看
Look!
对啊 我说的就是"卢克"
Ay, yes, I said "Luke".
你纠正过我 我发音是对的啊
You told me already. I did it right!
不是 我让你看
No! Look!
好汉不回头 别回头
Never look back. Never!
或许还有抢救的机会
Maybe we can salvage it?
没吓坏吧 宝贝
Are you okay, papi?
没事
Yeah.
那就好 因为我们有天使守护啊
Good. That's because we had our guardian angel.
妈呀 蜘蛛
Ay! A spider!
妈
Hey, mom?
瞧瞧
Check it.
口香糖
The gum!
你摆得真漂亮 宝贝 放桌上
Oh, and you made it pretty. Honey, put it on the table.
-也算新传统了吗 -当然
- New tradition? - Oh, yes. Yes.
圣诞口香糖
Christmas gum.
我尝尝
I take one.
好汉难为无"树"之饰啊 对吧
Tough to decorate the tree with no tree, huh?
你打算什么时候理我啊小卡
How long you gonna ignore me, cam?
直到人家心中云淡风轻
Until the shame cloud clears.
我就这样 我喜欢主动 强人所难
You know, I push. I'm a pusher.
你得好好冷静一下
You gotta give yourself a break.
其实吧 我这人
See, the thing about me,
我不像你那么热衷于表达情感
I'm not as open with feelings as you.
你不能期望每个人都像你那样
You've gotta lower your expectations.
我懂了
Oh, I get it.
-小步小步地来 -一步都要不得
- Baby steps. - No steps.
就这么着
This is it.
瞧 我又自作自受了
See? Did it again.
推 推 推 推
Push! Push, push, push, push.
我都把你推出房间了
Now I've pushed you out of the room.
就那样吧
That's fine.
修好了吗
How is she?
我把她翅膀上的轮胎印给擦了
I got the tire marks off her wings,
但头接不上了
but I can't get her head to stay on.
该口香糖大显身手了
Okay, that's what this is for.
把它粘在脖子那儿
Now stick it in the top of the tree
让没坏的地方朝外 来吧
with the good part facing out. Come on.
填充馅料看起来不错啊
Well, that stuffing looks good.
现在只需要一只火鸡将之包起来
All we need now is a turkey to surround it.
放松啦 菲尔刚发来短信
Well, relax. Phil just texted,
说他"马上就到蜡"
and he's "On his wax."
好了 圣诞树驾到
Okay! Here comes the tree.
终于到了
Oh! Finally!
-圣诞树残肢也驾到了 -嗨 宝贝
- Here comes more of the tree. - Hi, honey.
老天爷啊 什么情况啊
oh. Oh, my gosh. What happened?
它遭遇了车祸
Well, uh, someone ran over it,
不过没关系 我们会把树再拼起来
But that's okay 'cause we are gonna put it back together.
马上拼好
Right now.
那他得嚼不少口香糖啊
He's gonna need a lot of gum.
感谢苍天 菲尔终于带着"小胖墩"回来了
Oh, thank god. Here comes phil and the butterball.
我有名字的
I have a name.
我很抱歉 没有火鸡
I am sorry, but there is no turkey.
没有火鸡 不是都说好了吗 菲尔
There's no turkey? What's the plan, Phil?
迷你童子鸡
Cornish game hens.
如果你仔细看
If you get real close,
跟火鸡神似 而且不用大家分着吃
They look like turkeys, and everyone gets their own.
好有趣耶
Sounds like fun.
一点趣也没有 一点没有
Not fun. Not fun.
我让你买的是烹饪过的火鸡
I asked you to pick up a cooked turkey.
火鸡已经卖光了
The store was out of turkeys.
离我们的"特快圣诞"只有一小时了
It was an hour to express Christmas.
拜托 就凑合着用吧 好吗
Please, just make it work, okay? Please.
这些鸡都没解冻
They're not even defrosted.
行 克莱尔
Fine, Claire.
-你想给鸡解冻吗 -是啊
- You want 'em defrosted? - Yeah.
圣...
Merry...
他妹的
Freaking....
诞快乐
Christmas!
菲尔
Phil!
那是我的电击枪吗
Is that my stun gun?
没错 而且它还特好使呢
Yep. And it works great.
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
我们能行的 我们可以做到的
Um... We can make this work. This can work.
爸 你和米奇尔把树重新拼好
Dad, you and Mitchell reassemble that tree.
好的
All right.
我来把这些小鸡解冻
And I am going to defrost these birds,
然后我们一个一个来烤它们
and we'll cook them in shifts,
然后我们把晚餐时间稍微延迟一下就好
And we'll just push dinner back by a bit.
推多久啊 我还要参加派对呢
Oh, how long? 'Cause I still have my party.
-这天使怎么了 -不
- What the hell happened to the angel? - No!
现在真正的问题是
The real question here is,
那个狗头装饰怎么还在我们家
how come we still have the dog butler?
你在阁楼里发现了 是吧
Oh, you found him, huh?
这天使 好 好脏啊
Well, this thing is-- it's filthy.
而且 怎么回事啊
And... What happened?!
它也遭遇车祸了
It got run over.
肇事者很有可能跟碾过树的是一个人
Probably by the same maniac who ran over the tree.
我的天啊 这是
Oh, my God. Is that--
是 是口香糖 口香糖
Yep. Yep, that's gum. That is gum.
行 我 我不干了
Okay, I'm... I'm out.
-米奇尔 -我退出 我不玩了
- Ah, Mitch... - I'm done. I am out.
不 火鸡也没有 树也没有
No. No turkey, no tree,
而且小天使看起来就像被五马分尸
And now this looks like the lady she used to be
简直是成仙之前的惨相
before she died and became an angel.
好了 放松 米奇尔 装饰而已
All right. Relax, Mitchell. It's an ornament.
不是 他说的对
No, he's right.
今年的圣诞节是没法好好过了
We're never gonna get this together.
-我要去派对玩了 -不 你不能去
- I'm going to my party. - No, no. No, you're not.
你不能去 你得呆在这
You are not. You're staying right here,
因为你不能在圣诞节抛弃你的家人
Because you're not going to abandon your family on Christmas.
这又不是圣诞节
It's not Christmas.
就是 就是 这不是圣诞节 克莱尔
Exactly. Exactly. It's not Christmas, Claire.
好啊 行
Okay, fine!
行 说实话
Fine! You know what?
全靠我一人努力 真是心力交瘁
I am really tired trying to make this work on my own.
我们明年再见
I will see you people in a year.
还得再加9天
And nine days.
不行 谁都不许走
No! Nobody goes anywhere.
我知道问题出在哪里了
I know what the problem is here.
你们两个想妈咪了
You two miss your mommy.
没 我才没想妈咪呢
No. I do not miss my mommy.
承认吧 是挺悲哀的
Admit it. It's sad.
是她以前给你们烤饼干 还有那天使
She used to make you cookies, the angel...
现在她却用简讯和你们聊天
Now she talks to you in a newsletter
而且她还无故放你们鸽子
And she cancels for no reason.
到这来 我的小宝贝们
Come here, my little ones.
不用了
No, it's fine.
我们没事 没啥大不了的
We're good. It's not a big deal.
今天是圣诞节 你们需要妈咪
It's Christmas. You need a mommy.
你又不是我们的妈咪
You're not our mommy.
这也不是圣诞节啊 快过来
And it's not Christmas. Come here.
想妈妈没啥大不了的
It's okay to miss her.
我可以略微表达一下对"假圣诞"的看法吗
Can I put in my 2 cents on fake Christmas?
是特快圣诞啦
Express Christmas.
算了吧 菲尔 强辩也无法使之成立
Let it go, Phil. It's not sticking.
它需要时间
It needs time.
我们都为办好这事尽了最大努力了
We all gave it our best shot to make this thing work.
但它就是成不了 对吧
It just didn't happen, all right?
我们现在仍可以扭转烂局
What do you say we cut our losses?
去一家特好的中餐馆
Let's go out to a nice chinese restaurant
然后过一个传统的犹太圣诞节怎么样
and have a traditional jewish Christmas.
但是我还冒着生命危险去了杂货铺呢
But I risked my life grocery shopping.
这故事你留着给王福讲吧
Save that story for Wang Fu.
现在咱们走 出发 大家伙
Now let's go. Come on, everybody.
我请客 大家都走
On me! Out! Everybody out!
去王福那家 我请
Wang Fu's. It's on me.
快走 来吧 宝贝
Let's go. Come on, baby girl.
快点 宝贝
Come on, honey.
-什么情况 -太赞了
- What's going on? - Awesome!
你讨厌中国菜
You hate chinese food.
不赖吧
Not bad, huh?
杰啊 杰啊 杰啊
Jay, Jay, Jay.
-你想要抱我 是吧 -我是有点想
- You wanna hug me, don't you? - I kind of do.
给你4/5秒
4 to 5 seconds.
-能抱45秒 -4至5秒
- 45 seconds? - 4 to 5 seconds.
好吧
Oh, okay.
家人就是家人
Family is family.
无论是生来就血脉相连的
Whether it's the one you start out with...
-嗨 妈妈 -嗨 妈妈
- Hi, mom! - Hi, mom!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
那个 把你那个新男友的情况
So, um, tell us everything
-都告诉我们 -没错
- about the new boyfriend. , yeah.
一丝不落地全告诉我们哈
Don't leave anything out. Mm.
私密性事就不要说了
You can leave some things out.
亦或是相伴余生的
the one that you end up with...
又或是开枝散叶 收获的小家庭
Or the family that you gain along the way...
跟我一起 雪天使
Do this. Snow angels.
有家人在 每天都是
Which makes every day
体验圣诞日
December 16th.
杰 那个 不好意思把棒球卡弄坏了
Hey, Jay, um, I'm sorry about the baseball card.
我又 又给你准备了一个备份礼物
I-I did get you a-a backup gift.
其实没什么啦 我在加油的时候随手买的
It's--it's nothing. I picked it up when we stopped for gas.
狗狗鹿角
Dog antlers.
我知道 你给我们准备了雪
I know. You got us snow,
-而我只给你狗狗鹿角 -我爱这东西
- and I got you dog antlers. - I love these.
我想你可能会喜欢
I thought you might.
宝贝 看 快过来
Honey, look. Come here.
戴上 多萌啊
There. How cute is that?
我相机呢 歌洛莉亚 你得过来看看
Where's my camera? Gloria, you gotta see this!
过来 斯黛拉 歌洛莉亚
Come on, Stella! Gloria!
-狗狗鹿角 -他居然爱狗狗鹿角
- Dog antlers. - He loves dog antlers.
不 不 好吧
Oh, no. Oh, okay.
天啊
Oh. Oh, gosh!
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.